[Focus In]
天井って書いてある
だけなんですけど｡
何じゃ こりゃ～!?
山海塾ｱﾙか？
なんで ｵﾚが 暗黒舞踏
やらなきゃいけねえんだよ！
うわぁ！ こっちの部屋も？
しかも わかりにくいよ そのﾎﾞｹ！
ｵﾚ 真っ白だよ！
色 ついてないよ！
見えるはずの 天井がない｡
っていうか➡
何これ!? おい 神楽 大変だぁ！
周りを見ろよ ｵﾚだけじゃなくて➡
っていうか 世界そのものが
真っ白なんですけど！
どうなってんの？ これ！
何これ？ 何これ？
(銀時)ふぁ～… あれ？
なんか変だぞ…
いつもなら 目を覚ますと➡
あれ？ あれ？ あれ～？
おい 神楽～！
(いびき)
こら 起きろ 神楽！
(神楽)う～ん…｡
銀ちゃん どうしたｱﾙか？
顔が 真っ白ｱﾙ｡
なにｱﾙか？
朝っぱらから うるさいｱﾙなぁ｡
お前も 部屋も
何もかも 真っ白なんだ！
[Gintoki]
[Ceiling (morning)]
あれ？ ﾎﾝﾄｱﾙ…
いったい どうなってるｱﾙか？
Hm? Something's not right.
こっちが聞きてえよ｡
よっ！
The ceiling I usually see when I wake up isn't here today.
あれ？ なんか
動きが ｶｸｶｸしてるｱﾙ｡
Actually, I just see the word, "ceiling" up there.
そうなんだよ｡
なんか ｽﾑｰｽﾞじゃねえんだよ｡
[Background Odd Jobs
Japanese-style room]
[Pillar]
[Screen door]
Huh? Huh? What?
それに しゃべっても
口 動かねえで➡
変な名札みたいのが
出るだけだし…｡
What the hell is this?!
[Gintoki]
I'm all white! I'm not colored in.
この 空中に浮いてる番号は
いったい 何あるか？
Actually, this whole world is all white.
わからん… とにかく 何か
恐ろしいことが➡
What the hell's going on?
怒っているのは 確かだ｡
What is this? What is this? What the hell?
あ…｡
新八が来た｡
Hey Kagura, this is terrible!
[Footsteps]
(新八)おはようございます｡
[Gintoki]
Yikes, this room too?!
[Footsteps]
Hey, Kagura!
新八 大変だ！
ｵﾚたち 色ついてない！
Hey, wake up!! Kagura!!
っていうか 新八
お前も 真っ白ｱﾙ！
[Kagura]
わかってますよ｡
(２人)え!?
What is it? Why are you making so much noise in the morning?
わかってんの？
じゃ 教えてくれ 新八！
いったい 何が どうなってんだ？
Hey, what's wrong with you, Gin-chan? Your face is all white.
なんで こんなんなってるｱﾙか？
ﾌｩ… すべて ﾔﾂのせいなんですよ｡
(２人)ﾔﾂ？
Are you in the Sankai Juku?
[Note: Sankai Juku is an internationally known Butoh dance troupe. Performers typically have shaved heads and bodies covered in white rice powder.]
[Gintoki]
Now why on earth would I be in the Sankai Juku dance troupe?
これは ｢線撮り｣です！
Besides, not everyone will get that joke.
線撮り？
何ｱﾙか？ それ！
Take a look around. It's not just me.
通常 ﾃﾚﾋﾞｱﾆﾒは 基本となる
原画を描き➡
You, your room, and everything else is all white, too.
[Kagura]
Oh yeah, you're right.
What's going on?
その間を割っていく 動画｡
[Gintoki]
That's what I wanna know.
色をつける 彩色｡
[Kagura]
それに 背景をつけて
撮影するという➡
Huh? I feel so disjointed.
工程を経て
完成するんですが｡
おい そこ
色 ついてるぞ｡
[Gintoki]
I know. It's just not smooth.
これは BANKです｡
And when I talk, my mouth doesn't move either.
で 作業の途中 どうしても
完成しないまま➡
And this weird nametag thing keeps popping up.
ｱﾌﾚｺなどをしなくては
ならないとき➡
[Kagura]
What's this number floating in the air?
原画など 線画の状態で
撮影すること｡
[Gintoki]
I don't know. All I know is that something terrifying is happening.
それが
線撮りです｡
声優の皆さんには
お馴染みですね｡
Ah...
なんだって？ ｷﾊﾞﾔｼ！
じゃ 今週の 『銀魂』は➡
[Gintoki]
Oh, Shinpachi is here.
完成してないのか？
ひょっとして➡
[Shinpachi]
Good morning.
[Front entrance]
最後まで 真っ白ｱﾙか？
[Gintoki]
Shinpachi, this is terrible. We're not colored in!
いいえ 今週は ３人で手分けして
ｺﾝﾃを切ってますから➡
[Kagura]
Actually Shinpachi, you're all white too.
ｽｹｼﾞｭｰﾙを落としてるのは
この ｱﾊﾞﾝﾊﾟｰﾄの１人だけです｡
[Shinpachi]
I know that.
[Kagura, Gintoki]
Huh?
[Gintoki]
You know?
はぁ… よかったｱﾙ｡
Then tell us, Shinpachi.
What the heck is going on?
ずっと このままだったら
どうしようかと思ったｱﾙ｡
Why is this happening?
[Kagura]
おい 神楽
いつの間に着替えた？
[Shinpachi]
あぁ それはｺｽﾁｭｰﾑ違いの
ﾘﾃｰｸｶｯﾄです｡
It's all that guy's fault.
[Kagura, Gintoki]
That guy?
(神楽)そういう銀ちゃんだって
なんか 変ｱﾙ｡
[Shinpachi]
This is "line photography."
[Gintoki]
Line photography?
えっ？
作監作業が
間に合ってないんですよ｡
[Kagura]
What is that?
[Key animation]
(神楽)ﾌﾞﾌ… ﾌﾞﾌﾌﾌ…
変な顔～！
[Shinpachi]
Usually, a television animation production starts out with a storyboard.
ｸｿ～！
いったい どうなってんだ～！
[In-between animation]
In-between animation is interspersed throughout.
あ～ 何だ？ これ…｡
[Color]
なんか すごく
簡単な絵になってる！
Color is added and then the background.
ああ… 原画も間に合わなくなって
｢ﾗﾌ原｣になっちゃいましたね｡
This is the process it goes through before photography.
[Photography]
[Gintoki]
Hey, there's color in those.
(神楽)もう
誰が誰だか わからないｱﾙ！
[Shinpachi]
These are archives.
ﾁｷｼｮｳ！ 誰だ？
この原因を作った➡
During this process, there may be times when they have to do
ｺﾝﾃ遅らせて
ｽｹｼﾞｭｰﾙ なくしたﾔﾂは!?
the voice-overs before the animation is completed.
監督に言って ｸﾋﾞにしてもらおう｡
いったい どこのどいつだ!!
[Line photography]
They have no choice but to photograph the line drawings from the original pictures.
その監督です！
This is what we call line photography.
The voice actors who do voice-overs are familiar with this, right?
[Gintoki]
What, Kibayashi? That means this week's GinTama hasn't been completed yet?
[Note: Kibayashi is from the manga, MMR (Magazine Mystery Reportage).]
[Kagura]
So you're telling me it'll be all white till the end?
[Shinpachi]
No. We have three people working on this week's storyboard.
The only one behind schedule is the guy working on this introduction part.
Phew, thank goodness.
[Wearing a different costume]
[Kagura]
I wasn't sure what I'd do if we stayed like this till the end.
[Gintoki]
Hey, Kagura. When did you change?
[Shinpachi]
Oh, that's a retake of the wrong costume.
[Kagura]
Come to think of it, Gin-chan, you look different, too.
[Gintoki]
Huh?
[Shinpachi]
The animation director has yet to correct the key animations.
[Kagura]
You look weird!
[Gintoki]
Dammit, what's happening here?
Oh man, what the heck is this? We've turned into very simple drawings.
[Shinpachi]
Oh, looks like even the key animation isn't done on time and all we have are the rough drafts.
You can't tell who's who anymore.
[Kagura]
[Gintoki]
Dammit. Who's responsible for this?
Who's the one who lost the schedule so the storyboard was late?
I'll tell the director and have him fired.
Who the hell was it?
[Shinpachi]
It was the director himself!
[Gintoki]
[Taizo Hasegawa (38 years old), also known as Madao has finally found a new job.]
[If he can lead a steady life with this job, then there's something he's decided to do...]
♪♪～
[TEL]
(ﾊﾂ)もしもし？
[TEL](長谷川)ああ ｵﾚだ…｡
Hello.
Oh, it's me.
(ﾊﾂ)あら 珍しいわね｡ あなたから
電話かけてくるなんて…｡
How unusual for you to call me.
何かあった？
[TEL]いや… 別に…｡
Did something happen?
No, not especially...
[TEL]なんか用ないと
電話したら ﾀﾞﾒなのか？
I can't call you unless something bad has happened?
いやねぇ 何？ その言い方｡
Oh my, do you have to talk to me like that?
ｹﾝｶするために 電話してきたの？
Are you calling to pick a fight with me?
ちゃんと ご飯食べてる？
Are you eating well?
ｺﾝﾋﾞﾆ弁当ばっかり食べてちゃ
ﾀﾞﾒよ｡
You can't just eat fast food boxed lunches, you know.
[TEL]うるさいよ お前！
ｶﾞｷじゃあるまいし…｡
Oh, cut that out. I'm not a kid, you know.
I know. You're a full-fledged adult. That's why you need to eat properly.
そうよ｡
もう いい歳してんだから➡
ちゃんとしたもの 食べなきゃ｡
で 何があったの？
[TEL]えっ！
So? What happened?
Huh?
(ﾊﾂ)何か いいこと
あったんでしょ｡
Something good happened, right?
[TEL]別に…
たいしたことじゃねえけど…｡
It's nothing special...it's just that, I...
[TEL]あの あれ… ｵﾚさぁ…｡
(長谷川)仕事 決まった｡
[TEL](ﾊﾂ)ﾎﾝﾄに？ おめでとう！
...found a job.
Really? Congratulations!
まぁ
たいしたとこじゃないんだけど➡
It's nothing that spectacular, but at least it's a stable job.
ちゃんと 安定した仕事だ｡
[TEL]そう！ よかったわね！
Really? That's wonderful.
[TEL]じゃあ… 就職祝いしなくちゃ｡
This calls for a celebration.
いいよ そんなの別に…
初の 就職じゃあるめえし｡
Never mind that. It's not like this is my first job or anything.
いいのよ 私におごらせて｡
That's okay. Let me treat you.
あなたが いちばん苦しいときに➡
I couldn't do anything for you when you were down-and-out.
私 何も 手伝って
あげられなかったんだから｡
ﾊﾂ… あの…｡
Hatsu... Um...
[TEL]ｵﾚが この仕事
しばらく続けて➡
Once I start this job and my life becomes stable, can you and I...start over...?
生活が安定したら ｵﾚたち…
やり直す…｡
(破牙)ﾊﾂさん｡
あっ｡
Hatsu-san.
夜景でも見られているんですか？
Are you enjoying the night view?
ごめん… あとでかけ直す｡
Ah... I'm sorry, I'll call you later.
[TEL](長谷川)えっ おい ちょっ…｡
Huh? Hey, wait-
(電話の切れる音)
あぁ？ 男？
Huh? A man?
間違いねえ…
ありゃ 男の声だった｡
I'm pretty sure it was a man's voice.
ｿｲﾂの声がしたとたん
電話 切っちまってよ…｡
As soon as she heard his voice, she hung up.
どういうことだよ いったい…｡
What's going on? Is that guy more important than me?
ｵﾚより ｿｲﾂのほうが
大事だってのかい？
これ 不倫だよ 不倫！
不倫って…｡
That's adultery. Adultery!
Adultery? But weren't you two divorced a long time ago?
ｱﾝﾀら夫婦 とっくに
別れてなかったっけ？
人聞きの悪いこと言うな！
別居してるだけだ｡
Don't be disrespectful! We've just been separated.
離婚届に判を押した覚えはねえ！
I don't remember putting my seal on any divorce papers.
浮気調査ね…｡
You want me to investigate an extramarital affair?
知り合いだけに 気乗りしねえな｡
I'm really not interested since I know you and all.
I'll pay you well.
報酬は はずむぞ…
もう ｵﾚはﾌﾘｰﾀｰじゃない｡
I'm no longer just a freelancer, you know.
ﾌﾘｰﾀｰじゃないって…｡
No longer just a freelancer?
飲み屋で意気投合した
ﾀﾞﾒｵﾔｼﾞの会社だろ？
You're working for some loser ol' man that you hit it off with at some bar, right?
あてになんのか？
失礼なこと言うなよ！
You sure he's reliable?
Don't be rude.
確かに 一流企業とは言えねえが➡
True, it may not be a top-notch firm,
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝ通勤ｵｰｹｰという
今どき珍しい好条件だぞ｡
but it's rare these days to find a company that lets me wear sunglasses to work.
それって もしかして…
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝだらけで➡
You sure all their workers don't wear sunglasses and sell white powder?
白い粉などを
販売する会社じゃね？
よくわかったな！
あと ﾁｬｶとかいうのも➡
How did you know? They also sell something called "chaka."
[Note: Chaka is gangster slang for "gun."]
売ってるらしい…
よくわからんが 何だろうな？
Not sure what that is.
やめたほうがよくね？
心配いらねえ｡
I think you should quit.
Don't worry about it.
ｸﾞﾗｻﾝかけてるﾔﾂに
悪いﾔﾂはいねえ！
Anyone who wears sunglasses can't be bad. They're just shy.
みんな ｼｬｲなだけだよ｡
ｼｬｲなﾔﾂは そんな丈の短い
恥ずかしいｽﾞﾎﾞﾝ はかねえよ｡
Shy guys don't wear such embarrassingly short pants.
うるせえな！
これは 初就職のとき➡
Shut up. Hatsu bought me this suit when I first got a job.
ﾊﾂが買ってくれたｽｰﾂなんだよ｡
Humph. If you keep thinking about your woman,
ﾌﾝｯ… 女のことばっか考えてたら
また 仕事失敗して➡
you'll fail at your new job again and screw up any chance of getting back together with her.
ﾖﾘ戻すもｸｿもなくなるぜ｡
そっちはｵﾚに任せて
ｱﾝﾀは せいぜい➡
Leave that part of your life to me and you just focus on not getting fired, okay?
またｸﾋﾞにならないよう
気をつけるんだな｡
あんがとよ｡
...Thanks.
Gin-san, I'm gonna do it.
銀さん ｵﾚ やるわ！
今度こそ 今度こそ
幸せをつかみとる！
This time, I'm gonna find happiness for sure.
ﾍﾏすんなよ…｡
Don't screw it up now.
Huh?
♪♪～
あれ…？
(女)ｷｬ～ 痴漢よ！
Pervert!
えぇっ!? 違う！ これは…｡
No, no. This is...
It's the Kinniku Buster! Kinniku Buster!
[Note: Kinnikuman's trademark attack and one of 48 killer moves. From Ultimate Muscle.]
(女)ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰよ！ ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰだわ!!
[Edo Police]
[Interview room 1]
縄は持ってきてくれたか？
Did you bring me a rope?
人１人 吊るしても
ちぎれないくらいの丈夫な縄｡
A strong one that won't break even if a person hangs from it.
いや… 売り切れて なかった｡
No, they were all sold out. But instead...
その代わり… はい これ｡
...Here take this.
嫁さんの調査報告書｡
The investigation report on your wife.
自分の目で確かめな｡
Go ahead and check it with your own eyes.
Is she guilty or not?
白か？ 黒か？
生きてりゃいいことあるさ｡
Something good is bound to happen if you're alive.
白なのか？ 黒なのか？
明日は明日の風が吹く｡
Is she guilty or not?
Tomorrow is another day.
だから白か？ 黒か？
あれ？ 髪 切った？
I'm asking you, is she guilty or not?
Hey? Did you get a haircut?
[Note: Spoof of Cozy Tomita, who impersonates Tamori.]
殺せよ！ ｵﾚを殺せ～っ!!
Kill me! Just kill me!
どうせｵﾚなんか生きてたって➡
Even if I'm alive, I'm just destined to dance a bloody rondo all my life.
一生 血みどろのﾛﾝﾄﾞを
踊り続けるんだよ！
もう ずっと苦しみの螺旋階段を➡
I'll have to keep climbing a tortuous spiral staircase.
延々 上り続けるんだよ！
もう すべて終わりにしてくれ!!
Just end it all for me.
お前らもさぁ どうせ ｵﾚが
痴漢したって疑ってんだろ！
I'm sure you guys suspect me of performing lewd sex acts.
そりゃそうだよ！
嫁さんにも見捨てられるような➡
I don't blame you.
After all, my own wife walked out on me!
男だもんな ｵﾚは！
電車にひかれそうになって
気がついたら➡
The train almost hit us and before I knew it, I was doing the Kinniku Buster move.
ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰなんて お前ら どうせ➡
But you wouldn't believe that anyway, right?
信じてくれるわきゃねえよな！
赤の他人のﾃﾒｴらが 無罪だなんて
あれは事故だなんて➡
Total strangers like you guys would never believe
I'm innocent or that it was an accident, right?
信じてくれるわきゃねえよな！
ﾊﾞｯｷｬﾛ～ｯ！
You idiot!
(看守)ｷﾐ！ なにやってんだ!?
What the hell are you doing?
赤の他人だと？
そんなこと思ってんなら➡
Total strangers? If I thought that way, I wouldn't be here.
こんなとこ来やしねえよ！
赤の他人と思ってんなら➡
If I thought of you as a total stranger,
then I wouldn't give a damn which slammer you're in...
どこぶちこまれようが 死のうが
構いやしねえよ！
...or if you're dead!
赤の他人と思ってんなら…｡
If I thought of you as a total stranger...
こんなもん 貸し借りなんて
しやしねえんだよ!!
...then I wouldn't borrow or lend you this!
You totally suspect me!
完全に疑ってるよね？
これさ もう確定してるよね!?
It's confirmed now.
[The Pervert]
違うからね これは！
It's not like that, okay?
I can differentiate between fiction and reality.
ﾌｨｸｼｮﾝと現実の区別くらい
つくからね！
ｵﾚはやってないからね ｵﾚは！
I'm innocent!
わかってる わかってるって
信じてる 信じてる ﾋﾞﾘｰﾌﾞ｡
I know, I know.
I believe you. I believe you. Believe!
Really. You really believe me, right?
いや ﾎﾝﾄだよね？
ﾎﾝﾄ信じてるよね？
しつけえな…
信じてるって言ってんだろうが｡
God, enough already. He said he believes you, didn't he? Man, you're gross.
気持わりいんだよ｡
That's not the face of trust.
(長谷川)人を信じてる目じゃ
ないんだけど！
She's looking at me like I'm trash.
ｺﾞﾐを見る目つきなんだけど
この子！
ちげえよ… そういうのに
敏感な年頃だろ？
You're wrong. Girls this age are sensitive to stuff like that.
これくらいの子は…｡
ちょ… あんまり近づくな 神楽!!
危ないぞ！
Hey, don't get too close, Kagura. He's dangerous.
長谷川さん いまだに
取り調べは続いてるんですか？
Hasegawa-san, is the investigation still going on?
あぁ 今日で７日目か…｡
Yeah, today's the seventh day.
取り調べっつうより
恐喝に近いが➡
Although I feel more like I'm being threatened than investigated...
否認は続けてるが
精神も肉体も限界がきてる｡
I've been denying the allegations, but my mind and body are at its limit.
(長谷川)正直
もう 耐えられる気がしねえ！
Honestly, I don't think I can take anymore.
((ﾃﾒｴがやったんだろ！
記念ﾊﾞｽﾀｰか!!))
Huh? You did it, didn't you?
The Kinniku Buster!
ﾊﾂという最後の砦が
崩れちまった今➡
Now that Hatsu, my last sanctuary, has been destroyed,
もう何もかも
どうでもよくなっちまった！
I just don't care what happens anymore.
ｵﾚたちに やれることはねえのか？
Isn't there anything we can do?
まず ﾂﾊﾞを吐くのをやめろ！
For starters, stop spitting on me.
(長谷川)あとは 丈夫な縄だ！
After that, a strong rope.
長谷川さん！
Hasegawa-san!
ﾍﾍｯ 冗談さ！ もう疲れた｡
I'm kidding.
I'm tired... Sorry, but can you all leave now?
悪いけど帰ってもらえるか？
(破牙)長谷川さんですね？
You're Hasegawa-san, right?
There's something I'd like to talk to you about.
(破牙)ちょっと
お話ししたいことが…｡
誰だ？ ｱﾝﾀ｡ ﾊｯ！
Who are you?
私 ２日後にあなたが立たされる➡
I'm Haga, the prosecutor in the court of law where you will be tried in two days.
白洲の場にて検事を務めます
破牙と申します｡
要するに長谷川さん
あなたの敵ですよ｡
In other words Hasegawa-san, I am your enemy.
Prosecutor Haga.
破牙検事
数々の詮議において➡
The remarkable prosecutor who has convicted many criminals in examinations.
容疑者を有罪に導いてきた
凄腕検事｡
奉行所きってのｴﾘｰﾄか…｡
An elite in the magistrate's office.
こりゃ 以前のﾏﾀﾞｵならまだしも➡
The Madao of the past may have been able to deal with him, but now that he's...
性犯罪者になりさがった
今のﾏﾀﾞｵでは➡
degraded himself into a sex offender he won't be able to compete with him at all.
太刀打ちできないｱﾙ！
That's not true, Kagura.
そんなことないよ 神楽ちゃん｡
長谷川さんは お金も運もないけど
ｶﾞｯﾂだけは誰にも負けないよ！
Hasegawa-san may not have money or luck,
but he's got more guts than anyone I know.
男は ﾊｰﾄだよ！
For a man, it's all about heart.
Besides, he didn't commit any lewd acts.
だいたい 痴漢やってないし！
(神楽)現実 見ろ！ 新八!!
Face reality, Shinpachi.
お前も 金ないと銀ちゃんみたいに
ﾓﾃない男になるｱﾙよ！
If you don't have money, you're going to end up unpopular like Gin-chan.
(神楽)だいたい 今のﾏﾀﾞｵには➡
Besides right now, that Madao...
唯一の取り柄のｶﾞｯﾂさえ
見受けられないね！
...doesn't even seem to have any guts.
(神楽)本物のﾏﾀﾞｵに
なりさがってしまったｱﾙ｡
He's become a real Madao now.
ｺｲﾂは なんだ？
What is this?
(破牙)見たとおり 離婚届です｡
ﾊﾂさんとあなたの…｡
It's exactly what you see...divorce papers for you and Hatsu-san.
私とﾊﾂさんは 結婚を前提に➡
I have been going out with Hatsu-san with the intention of marrying her.
おつきあい
させていただいています｡
なっ!?
文句を言う資格はあなたにはない｡
What?
You have no right to complain.
別居状態で
事実上 離婚しているのと➡
I hear you've been separated and practically divorced.
変わらない状態と聞いています｡
今 ここで はっきりと
別れていただきたい｡
I'd like you to officially put an end to it right here.
これに 判を押してもらえますか？
(長谷川)ふざけんな！
Please put your seal on this?
You gotta be kidding me.
なんで他人のお前に そんなこと
指図されなきゃならねえ！
Why should I take orders from an outsider like you?
(破牙)おや？ あなたも もう
ﾊﾂさんとは他人でしょう｡
You're no longer related to Hatsu-san either.
それとも
ﾖﾘでも戻すつもりでしたか？
Or were you planning on reconciling with her?
こんなところにいる あなたに
ﾊﾂさんを幸せにできると？
Can you, being in a place like this, really make her happy?
なっ…｡
それに言ったはずです｡
Besides, I already told you. I am your enemy.
私は あなたの敵だと｡
私の裁量しだいで ２日後の詮議➡
In two days, I can help decide if you are guilty or not.
あなたは
有罪にも無罪にもなるんですよ｡
この意味 わかりますよね？
I'm sure you understand what I mean.
判を押せば
あなたの無罪を約束しましょう｡
If you put your seal on this, I promise that you will be proven innocent.
押さなければ そうですね…｡
And if you don't...
Well, let's see...
(破牙)長谷川さん あなた
入国管理局を お辞めになるとき➡
Hasegawa-san, when you left the Department of Immigration Control,
幕府から切腹を命じられて
逃亡を図ったらしいですね！
I understand the Bakufu ordered you to commit seppuku,
[Note: Seppuku is a form of Japanese ritual suicide by disembowelment.]
but instead you chose to run away.
((うるせえって言ってんだ！
ﾌﾟﾁﾄﾏ星人！
I said shut up, you freakin' space flounder!
(上司)腹切れ｡
ﾏｼﾞっすか!?))
Commit seppuku.
Are you serious?
What will happen if I mention this during the questioning?
(破牙)これを詮議で言及すれば
どうなるか…｡
まぁ おそらく
ｸﾋﾞが とぶことになるでしょう｡
Well, most likely your head will roll.
よく お考えください 長谷川さん｡
Please give it some serious thought, Hasegawa-san.
まぁ どちらにしても
ﾊﾂさんは私のもの｡
Well, in either case, Hatsu-san is mine.
(破牙)どちらにしても
あなたには➡
And, what awaits you is the life of a loser.
負け犬の人生しか
待っておりませんがね｡
あの すみません｡
ん？
Um, excuse me.
万事屋 銀ちゃんは ここですか？
Is this the Odd Jobs?
そうですけど…｡
Yes, it is...
(ﾊﾂ)あぁ
じゃあ あなたが銀さん！
Oh, then you must be Gin-san.
(ﾊﾂ)あぁ ﾎﾝﾄに銀髪！
My, your hair really is silver.
長谷川 泰三が
いつも お世話になっております｡
Thank you for always taking care of Taizo Hasegawa.
私… 泰三の妻 ﾊﾂと申します｡
I'm Taizo's wife...Hatsu...
♪♪～
《長谷川:どうして… どうして
ｵﾚは いつも こうなんだ？
Why...
Why am I always like this?
少しでも幸せをつかみかけると
全速力で幸せが逃げていく》
Whenever I try to grab happiness, it runs away...
...at full speed.
はぁ…｡
《そう ﾊｲｼﾞ…
ｵﾚのなかには ﾊｲｼﾞが住んでいた｡
That's right...
It's Heidi. Heidi lives inside of me.
[Note: Refers to the TV animation version of Heidi.]
幸せの花が咲こうとすると➡
The flowers of happiness are about to bloom,
まだ芽しか出ていないのに➡
but an impatient Heidi picks them,
摘んでしまう 超 気の早いﾊｲｼﾞ》
even though they're only buds.
Heidi! It's too early. They haven't blossomed yet.
[Note: He looks like Peter from the TV animation version of Heidi.]
((ﾊｲｼﾞ！ それ まだ早え！
花 咲いてねえから！))
I tried to stop Heidi many times. But she would never listen to
《長谷川:ｵﾚは
何度もﾊｲｼﾞを止めた｡
でも ﾔﾂは ﾍﾟｰﾀｰの言うことに
耳を貸そうともしない｡
what Peter says.
もう ﾔﾂの強行を止めるには➡
The only way to put an end to her acts of violence
was to throw myself and her into the ravine of the Alps.
ﾔﾂを道連れに ｱﾙﾌﾟｽの谷底に➡
身を投げるしか
ないのかもしれない…》
Peter! No! I don't want to leave the mountains!
((ﾊｲｼﾞ:山を 離れたくな～い!!
You must die!
(長谷川)死なば もろとも～!!))
《そんなことばかり
ここ数日 考えている…》
That's all I've been thinking about the last few days.
(看守)面会だ｡
You've got a visitor.
よぉ｡ 縄は 持ってきてくれたか？
So, did you bring me a rope?
…取り引きを もちかけられた｡
He offered me a deal. That bastard prosecutor who's going out with Hatsu.
ﾊﾂと つきあってる
検事の野郎に…｡
(長谷川)離婚届に 判を押せと…｡
He told me to put my seal on the divorce papers.
[Note: In Japan, an official seal, used like a signature, is stamped on divorce papers.]
(長谷川)押さねば
詮議で ｵﾚを 打ち首にすると…｡
If I don't, he will make sure my head gets cut off at the trial.
…押すつもりでいる｡
未練がましく➡
I'm planning on putting my seal on it.
All I'm doing is dragging Hatsu down by not being able to let go
こんな 紙切れ１枚に
しがみついたところで➡
ﾊﾂの足を 引っ張るだけだ｡
and hanging on to this one piece of paper.
(長谷川)ﾀﾞﾒ旦那と別れて➡
I don't want to stand in Hatsu's way
新しい一歩を 踏み出そうとする
ﾊﾂのｼﾞｬﾏは したくねえ！
if she's trying to leave her hopeless husband and start a new life.
(長谷川)それに…
死にたくねえしな…｡
Besides, I don't wanna die.
(長谷川)ﾊﾊﾊ！ 笑えよ｡
Go ahead and laugh.
(長谷川)自分の命の惜しさに
ｵﾚは 嫁さん 売り渡すんだ｡
I'm gonna sell off my wife so I can save my precious life.
ｵﾚは…｡
I...
Your wife came to see me.
嫁さん 来たぜ｡
ｱﾝﾀに 連絡つかねえから
ｳﾁに来たらしい｡
She couldn't get in touch with you so she came to see me.
新しい仕事 がんばれ って…➡
She wanted to wish you good luck on your new job.
And she asked me to give you this.
ｱﾝﾀに これを 渡してくれってよ｡
Th-This is...
ｺ… ｺｲﾂは…｡
ｱｲﾂ 知らねえのか!?
ｵﾚが 捕まったこと…｡
She doesn't know...that I've been arrested?
さぁな…｡
I don't know. But I haven't told her anything.
ｵﾚは 何も話しちゃいねえよ｡
そんだけだ｡ じゃあな｡
Well, that's all I wanted to say. See ya.
あぁ それから 縄…
今度 来るとき 持ってくるよ｡
Oh yeah, and about that rope.
I'll bring it next time I come.
首 吊るための縄なんざ
用意するのは ごめんこうむるが➡
I have no intention of getting you a rope so you can hang yourself.
ｱﾝﾀを…➡
But...
ｱﾝﾀを 奈落から
引きずり上げるための縄なら➡
If it's a rope to pull you out of hell, then I'll bring you as many as you want.
いくらでも 用意してやらあ｡
覚えときな｡
Just remember that.
((ﾊｲｼﾞ:ｱﾊﾊﾊ！
ﾍﾟｰﾀｰ！
ﾍﾟｰﾀｰ それ 押してあげようか？
Peter!
Peter, you want me to stamp it?
I know you can't do it. I'll do it for you.
自分じゃ 押せないんでしょう？
私が 押してあげるよ｡
You don't wanna die, right?
死にたくないんでしょう？))
Heidi!
《ﾊｲｼﾞ～!! うぉぉぉ～っ!!》
((ﾊｲｼﾞ:ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
そうやって ｱﾝﾀは➡
Yeah, just like that, you keep living your life as a doggone loser.
ず～っと 負け犬として
生きていけばいいのよ！
Stop, Heidi!
(長谷川)やめろ ﾊｲｼﾞ～!!
That's perfect for you.
(ﾊｲｼﾞ)あなたには
それが お似合いよ！ ﾖｰｾﾞﾌ！
Joseph!!
[Note: Hasegawa is dressed up as Joseph from the TV animation version of Heidi.]
ﾊﾊﾊ…｡
You're right. I may be a doggone loser...
(長谷川)確かに
ｵﾚは 負け犬かもしれねえ…｡
But!
だが！ 犬は犬でも…！
Even if I'm a worthless mutt...
死ぬ前に
ﾙｰﾍﾞﾝｽの絵を見るほうの犬だ～!!
I'm the mutt who goes to see Rubens' painting before I die!!
[From the story "A Dog of Flanders"; a novel and anime about the boy Nello and his dog Patrasche. Nello and Patrasche freeze to death as they go to see Rubens' painting.]
覚えていろ～！
Just remember, I'll keep coming back!
私は 何度でも よみがえる！))
(笑い声)
《長谷川:戦わなきゃならねえ！
I gotta fight.
It's all over if a man loses his fangs.
男は 牙をなくしちゃ ｼﾒｰだ！
たとえ 負け犬になろうと➡
Even if I'm just a good-for-nothing mutt,
この牙が あるかぎり
最後まで 戦わなきゃならねえ！
as long as I've got fangs, I'll keep fighting till the end.
I'll be a dandy man who won't be defeated...
[Note: A MAkenai DAndy na Otoko or a Madao.]
それが 負けない ﾀﾞﾝﾃﾞｨな男！
ﾏﾀﾞｵだ！》
a Madao!
We will now start the trial for the Oedo Line Kinniku Buster molestation case.
(奉行)これより➡
大江戸線 ｷﾝ肉ﾊﾞｽﾀｰ痴漢事件の
詮議を 行う｡
The defendant, Taizo Hasegawa, please raise your head.
被告人 長谷川 泰三｡
おもてを あげい｡
(奉行)そこもと
この場でいたす証言は➡
You must swear on this document
ｳｿ偽りのないことを
この書面に 固く約束せい｡
that any testimony you give here is true.
If you break this promise,
以後 これに そむくことあらば➡
詮議の 如何に かかわらず
これを罰す｡
you will be subject to punishment regardless of the outcome of this trial.
《破牙よ…｡ ｵﾚを
打ち首にしたくば するがいい｡
Haga, if you want to cut my head off, then go right ahead.
But, I refuse to hand over Hatsu to a man who uses dirty tricks like you.
だが…
お前のような 汚い手を使う男に➡
ﾊﾂは 渡さん！
Even if my head gets chopped off, I'll bite your throat with just my head.
たとえ ｵﾚの首が飛ぼうと➡
首だけで お前の のど笛に
噛みついてやる！
ﾊﾂは… ﾊﾂは ｵﾚが守る！》
Hatsu...I will protect Hatsu!
んっ？ ちと 待ちなさい｡
Hang on a second.
被告人の 弁護の者が見当たらんが
どうした？
Who is representing the defendant? Where is he?
(警備官)それが…
まだ 来ておりません｡
Well...he's not here yet.
(警備官)道中
何か あったのやも しれませぬな｡
Perhaps something happened on his way here.
あ～ すんませ～ん！
遅れました～！
Oh, sorry. I'm late.
来る予定だった 下山弁護士が
痴漢で 捕まっちゃいまして…｡
Attorney Shimoyama, who was supposed to be here, was arrested on molestation charges,
代理で 来ました｡
so I'm his replacement.
I'm the attorney, Sakata.
弁護士の 坂田で～す！
よろしく お願いしま～す｡
Nice to meet you.
《…銀さん!?》
Gin-san?!
ここっすか？
ここ 座るんですか？
Here? Do I sit here?
(目付)靴 脱げ｡ 靴！
Take your shoes off. Your shoes.
《な… なんで!?
Why...?
戦ってくれるのか!?
So you're gonna help me fight?
ｵﾚと 一緒に…｡
You and me together?
だが 素人が 弁護なんて…》
But can an amateur defend me?
So shall we start, Mr. Prosecutor?
じゃあ 始めましょっか｡
検事さん｡
《長谷川:相手は
あの 破牙検事だぞ！》
We're up against that Prosecutor Haga, you know.
We will now start the trial.
それでは 詮議 開始！
[To be continued]
[Preview]
At 7:25 on February 21st, the defendant Taizo Hasegawa,
forcefully grabbed the hand of the victim, Ms. A,
on the platform at Kabukicho station and dragged her down into the railway.
He is suspected of performing a Kinniku Buster in front of everyone.
This is clearly an act of molestation and assault.
And depending on the circumstance, it may even be considered attempted murder.
Objection!
It's true that the defendant performed a Kinniku Buster on the victim.
However it is questionable as to whether he did this with the intent to molest.
And therefore, I plead that the defendant is not guilty.
["Men, Be A Madao"]
[Attorney Sakata vs. Prosecutor Haga. The battle has begun.]
[And will Hasegawa be able to win against the Heidi living inside him?]